Sergei Saprunov

Bangkok, Thailand | saprunovsergey@google.com | linkedin.com/in/sergei-saprunov

About

A professional, specializing in bringing value using machine learning and data analysis. I apply critical thinking and communication supported by disciplined and structured approach to tackle complex problems. Eager for a role in a forward-thinking, data-oriented international company where I can continue developing my skills and utilize my expertise to drive company towards its goals

Experience

Data Scientist, Unitiki - Remote

July 2023 - May 2024

- Implemented multiarmed bandit as a dynamic pricing tool, leading to the revenue increase by 7% at a cost of 2% turnover
- Refined existing AB testing solution by enhancing power and type-I error calculation, increasing platform accuracy and interpretability
- Optimized transport route search process by integrating machine learning regression model output as a metric used for a decision making process

Data Scientist, OMK CJSC, Chusovoy Metallurgical Works – Remote

Dec 2019 - Feb 2023

- Developed and implemented time series forecasting model to improve monthly production demand accuracy (60,000 tons per year) and smooth the seasonal effect
- Increased Vanadium extraction rate of the ferroalloy production workshop by 4% using a machine learning regression approach
- Implemented Tensorflow object detection model in order to improve painting line throughput via replacing malfunctioning painting line elements

Data Analyst, LoyaltyPlant – Saint Petersburg, Russia

June 2019 – Nov 2019

- Expanded and supported statistical exchange module on a linux server, increasing, the share of partners accessing app-related data by 60%
- Equipped Customer Success with actionable data and visualizations, dash.plotly dashboard, contributing to the communication and relationship-building with partners

Junior Data Analyst, Corona Auto – Saint Petersburg, Russia

Sept 2018 - Dec 2018

- Initiated and conducted switch from excel to python for forecasting, reducing analytics department operational load by 12%
- Elevated forecasting accuracy by 14%, lowering MAPE from 22% to 19% through switch from moving average to fbprophet

Education

SPbPU (Peter the Great St.Petersburg Polytechnic University), Specialist in Construction of unique buildings and structures

Sept 2011 – Aug 2017

XAMK (South-Eastern Finland University of Applied Sciences), Bachelor of Engineering in Construction of unique buildings and structures

Jan 2015 – Jan 2016

Skills

Languages: Russian - Native, English - C1 **Programming Languages:** Python, SQL, C

Developer Tools: Linux, Git, Docker

Frameworks: Pandas, Sklearn, Numpy, Dash, Matplotlib, Seaborn, Plotly, Tensorflow

BI Tools: Redash, Dash.plotly, Tableau